# Alicia Savelli

2220-3 Upper Middle Rd, Burlington ON, L7P 2Z9

**(**289) 828-0923 • ☑ aliciasavelli@gmail.com ⓐ aliciasavelli.github.io

I am an undergraduate student going into my final year of a physics degree at Brock University with previous Bachelor's degrees in mathematics and education. I am extremely passionate about astronomy, physics, mathematics, research, and teaching, and have significant experience and skills to support me in a career in science. I am interested in the fields of cosmology, galaxy formation and evolution, and relativity.

## **Education**

| Brock University B.Sc. Physics (Honours)  - 92% average in upper level courses (4.0 GPA on 4 point scale)  - 88% cumulative average (4.0 GPA on 4 point scale)  - Top 15% of faculty                       | 2020 – 2022                          |
|--|--------------------------------------|
| Brock University B.Sc. Mathematics (Honours), minor in Physics  - 93% average in upper level courses (4.0 GPA on 4 point scale)  - 88% cumulative average (4.0 GPA on 4 point scale)  - Top 15% of faculty | 2014 – 2019                          |
| Brock University B.Ed.   | 2014 – 2019                          |
| <ul> <li>Intermediate/Senior qualifications</li> <li>Straight P1s(As) – 94% cumulative average (4.0 GPA on 4 point scale)</li> </ul>   |                                      |
| Notre Dame Catholic Secondary School OSSD  - Ontario Scholar with 90% average in top six grade 12 courses  | 2010 – 2014                          |
| Research Experience  |                                      |
| Undergraduate Thesis.  |                                      |
| <b>Exploring the Possibility of Faster-than-Light Travel in Our Universe</b> <i>Supervisor: Prof. Barak Shoshany</i>   | <b>Brock University</b> 2020 – 2021  |
| Research Projects  |                                      |
| Analogues of the Milky Way in Cosmological Simulations Supervisors: Dr. Ted Mackereth & Dr. Josh Speagle   | University of Toronto<br>Summer 2021 |
| Untitled? Supervisors: Dr. Ted Mackereth & Dr. Josh Speagle  | University of Toronto<br>Winter 2022 |

#### **Publications**

#### Exploring the Possibility of Faster-than-Light Travel in Our Universe

Alicia Savelli, Barak Shoshany

In prep.

# Scholarships, Awards & Honours

#### Summer Undergraduate Research Program Fellowship

Canadian Institute for Theoretical Astrophysics; Dunlap Institute for Astronomy & Astrophysics, \$9,595

2021

## **SURP Student Spotlight**

Canadian Institute for Theoretical Astrophysics; Dunlap Institute for Astronomy & Astrophysics

2021

#### **SURP Poster Contest - Runner Up**

Canadian Institute for Theoretical Astrophysics; Dunlap Institute for Astronomy & Astrophysics

2021

#### Dean's Honour List

**Brock University** 

2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2021

- Awarded to students with an 80% average or greater each academic year
- Received every year of B.Sc. (Math) & B.Sc. (Physics) degrees
- Additional distinction of top 15% of the faculty

#### **Brock Scholars Award**

Brock University, \$8,000

2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

- Entrance scholarship for incoming averages of 90% or greater
- \$2,000/year for a maximum of 4 years, renewed if average is maintained at 80% or greater

## Ontario Scholar

Halton Catholic District School Board

2014

Distinction for graduating students with an average of 79.5% or greater in top six grade 12 courses

#### Top Hat Marching Orchestra Scholarship

Top Hat Marching Orchestra, \$1,000

2014

#### French Second Language Award

Halton Catholic District School Board, \$50

2014

- Awarded to graduating student with the highest mark in a grade 12 French course

## **Conference Talks**

SDSS-V

Johns Hopkins University/Online

Analogues of the Milky Way in Cosmological Simulations

August 2021

## **Conference Posters**

SDSS-V

Johns Hopkins University/Online

Analogues of the Milky Way in Cosmological Simulations

August 2021

# **Teaching Experience**

## Secondary Teacher

## Wembley High Technology College

London, UK

Secondary Maths Teacher

*September* 2019 – *July* 2020

- Taught five maths classes from the GCSE Foundation and Higher curricula to Key Stage 3 and Key stage 4 learners at various levels of academic achievement
- Developed and delivered engaging and differentiated lessons, managed classroom behaviour, regularly assigned and marked homework
  - Year 9 form tutor
- Volunteered to participate in and organize extra curricular activities such as a tutoring club, a puzzles club, a maths news letter, and UKMT national maths challenges

## St. John Henry Newman Catholic Secondary School (HWCDSB)

Hamilton, ON

Physics Student Teacher

*April – May 2019* 

- B.Ed. Practicum
- Taught one SPH3U grade 11 universy level physics class and two SPH4U grade 12 university level physics classes
- Entirely responsible for creating notes and lessons that delivered the curriculum, and developing and marking tests, quizzes, assignments, and lab experiments/reports
- Volunteered with the school's concert band and lunchtime and after-school tutoring/homework clubs

## Cathedral High School (HWCDSB)

Hamilton, ON

Math Student Teacher

November – December 2018

- B.Ed. Practicum
- Taught one MPM1D grade 9 academic level math class and one MCR3U grade 11 university level math class
- Entirely responsible for creating notes and lessons that delivered the curriculum, and developing and marking tests, quizzes, and assignments
  - Volunteered with the after-school homework club

## Primary Teacher

# Prince of Wales South Public School (NDSB)

Thorold, ON

Student Teacher

October 2015 – March 2016

- B.Ed. Practicum
- Delivered Levelled Literacy Intevervention (LLI) program
- Helped students of all ages advance their reading levels in small groups of three to four students

#### Professional Primary, Secondary, & Post-Secondary Tutor.....

## Oxford Learning

Burlington & Hamilton, ON

Teacher

May 2017 – Present

- Tutor in groups of one to three high school students, and occasionally students at the college or primary levels
- Specialize in intermediate and senior level math, calculus, data management, and physics, but also tutor students in chemistry, general science, English, French, and more

#### **Private Tutor**

Independent Private Tutor

2014 – Present

– One-on-one private tutoring in all levels and categories of secondary math and science and first-year math and physics

Other

## **Education Quality and Accountability Office**

Etobicoke, ON

Scorer

July 2019

- Scored academic- and applied-level grade 9 math EQAO tests

## **Brock University Mathematics Department**

St. Catharines, ON

Exam Proctor

2015-2016

- Proctored first-year math midterms and final exams

# **Other Relevant Work Experience**

McDonalds Canada Burlington, ON

Team Leader, Crew

2013 - 2019

- Responsibilities included area and shift management, customer service, order taking & filling, and birthday parties

- Transferable skills to research and education include strong leadership & team management, collaboration, time management, stress management, organization, and communication

ArcelorMittal Dofasco Hamilton, ON

Data Analyst

Summer 2018

- Developed and enhanced queries and data reports to improve company efficiency, wrote macros to supplement reports

- Enhanced technical skills with Visual Basic, SQL, MS Excel, and MS Access

# Workshops, Training, & Professional Development

#### CTA 200H Introduction to Python

**University of Toronto** 

Student

May 2021

- 2-week intensive introductory course to coding and data analysis with Python
- Covered topics such as advanced plotting, statistical analysis, and machine learning

#### **SURP Astro 101 Lecture Series**

**University of Toronto** 

Summer Research Student

Summer 2021

- Summer series of weekly introductory astronomy lectures
- Topics covered included planets & explanets, galaxy formation & evolution, instrumentation, statistics, cosmology, and black holes

## **SURP Professional Development Series**

**University of Toronto** 

Summer Research Student

Summer 2021

- Summer series of weekly professional development workshops and seminars
- Topics covered included careers in astronomy, grad school applications and experiences, and presenting research

Shutdown STEM University of Toronto

Attendee

July 2021

- Day-long workshop within the Astronomy & Astrophysics department pertaining to action against racism with a special focus on Indigenous peoples
- Workshop included presentations, discussions, and activities such as researching and letterwriting

## **SAFETALK Mental Health Training**

**Brock University** 

Attendee

March 2018

- Training in speaking to young people about their mental health and the best ways to be available

- Awarded certificate

## **Relevant Coursework**

- o Astronomy: Introduction to Astronomy, Planetary Science
- Physics: Classical Mechanics, Electromagnetism, Quantum Mechanics, Statstical Mechanics & Thermal Physics, Optics, Special & General Relativity, Experimental Physics
- o **Mathematics:** Calculus, Vector Calculus, Differential Equations, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Mathematical Physics, Differential Geometry
- **Computer Programming:** Mathematics Integrated with Computers and Applications I/II/III, Introduction to Scientific Computing
- o Education: Mathematics, Physics, Diversity, Special Education

## **Technical & Personal Skills**

- o Programming Languages: Python, Visual Basic, SQL, Physica, Extrema
- o Software: Maple, Mathematica, LATEX, Git
- o Operating Systems: Windows, Linux
- o Professional Skills: Presenting, writing, teaching
- o **Personal Skills:** Enthusiasm, organization, communication, time management, leadership, collaboration, perseverance, diligence

# **Professional Memberships**

**Ontario College of Teachers (OCT)** 

Member ID: 698209

2019 – Present

## **Extracurricular Activities**

| Burlington Concert Band         | Burlington, ON     |
|---------------------------------|--------------------|
| 1 <sup>st</sup> Clarinet        | 2018-2019          |
| Brock University Winds Ensemble | St. Catharines, ON |

 $2^{nd}$  Clarinet 2014-2018

Brock Intramural SportsBrock UniversitySoccer, Baseball, Volleyball2016-2018

# **Media Appearances**

| SURP Project Showcase <u>Poster</u> , Research Summary | 2021 |
|--|------|
| SURP Student Spotlight                                 | 2021 |
| Student of the Week interview                          | 2021 |

2017